# DAMIR ARACIC

I am an IT Generalist with a wide breadth of experience and an exceptional track record in ensuring timely project completion and a high level of customer satisfaction. My skills range from hands-on technical experience (system design, administration, and integration; software engineering, SDLC, Agile, use cases, UAT, Design Patterns, UML; Java, Python, Powershell, C#, C++; Visual Studio) to vendor management (HVE and LVE contracting, physical and virtual PBX infrastructure, telecommunications, MDM) to project management and analysis (PLC, stakeholder management, integration constraints, policy compliance, risk assessment). My professional experience is grounded in technical bedrock of BS and MS degrees in Computer Science.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **IT Manager**

**Charter Communications** 

2016 - 2019

- Helped the company meet goals in consolidating technology stacks and support models of
   (3) legacy companies into the new umbrella company by supporting technology needs of
   4K+ customers located at legacy company sites across multiple states;
- Saved company money both by realizing planned capital investment plans in completing various IT and Facilities projects of \$50k average worth on a quarterly basis and by proactively eliminating high costs of maintaining legacy infrastructure;
- Ensured timely project success and legal/policy compliance by managing relationships and facilitating communication between Technical Support and Business Leaders in (7) different cities on a daily basis;
- Increased productivity and satisfaction of Business Leaders with Technical Support by leading, developing, and managing IT component of 13 technicians across (5) states and (3) time zones.

## IT Systems and Network Administrator

**EOCF** 

2013 - 2016

- Supported all network infrastructure devices at 25 locations serving 300+ employees via 15 servers, 300+ workstations, 40+ MFPs, 60+ mobile devices, and multiple PBX phone systems;
- Designed, coordinated, and executed company-wide infrastructure upgrade worth \$800k over (3) years;
- Led and managed IT component of three (3) employees and an annual budget of \$50k;
- Managed company participation in and policy compliance to FCC USAC E-Rate.

# **Tech Specialist and Web Developer**

**EOCF** 

2007 - 2013

- Successfully automated company domain/email migration (MS Exchange 2003 to 2007);
- Implemented and maintained Windows deployment server (batch, Powershell, SQLServer);
- Maintained the existing agency website (PHP, HTML, XML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, MySQL);
- Automated various IT processes via scripting (shell, Python, C#, VB, Visual Studio);
- Responsible for network security, Active Directory, integrity of data, and inventory safety.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science (MS) in Computer Science
Bachelor of Science (BS) in Computer Science

Washington State University
Washington State University

### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request

## OTHER INFORMATION

US citizen; fluent in Croatian, conversational in German; 20-year resident of PNW